<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Stephen Wyatt Bush&rsquo;s Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-15T16:37:06-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Stephen Wyatt Bush]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build Conf 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/12/21/build-conf-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/12/21/build-conf-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/images/build-conference-logo.jpg" alt="Build Conference Logo" /></p>

<p>Early November I had the priviledge to attend <a href="http://2011.buildconf.com/">Build Conf</a> in Belfast, Ireland. Build is an amazing conference, organized by a <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/goodonpaper">fine young man</a>. The conference touched on design, development, and typography (three of my favorite things) with a star-studded list of attendees.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Oh, and <a href='#wilson-miner'>Wilson Miner gave the best presentation I&#8217;ve ever seen.</a></p>

<h3>First Night: Movies</h3>

<p>I arrived in Dublin on Monday at 8AM (1AM to my jet lagged body) and caught a bus to Belfast. The bus ride offered a fantastic view of the Irish countryside. On the evening of the first night, Build packed into a theatre and watched a selection of movies.</p>

<p><img src="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/images/movie-night.jpg" alt="Watching the films." />
<em>Watching the films. Credit to <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/fillyc/6345878100/sizes/z/in/set-72157628137095270/">fillyc</a>.</em></p>

<h4><a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1516705613/making-faces-metal-type-in-the-21st-century-a-do">Making Faces: Metal Type in the 21st Century</a></h4>

<p>The <a href="http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1516705613/making-faces-metal-type-in-the-21st-century-a-do">first movie</a> chronicled Jim Rimmer of P22 Type Foundry as he crafted his own type by hand. As a type nut, I found the entire documentary fascinating. Jim Rimmer drew his own letters, traced them, transferred them to metal, and ran them through a machine which transferred the letter to metal at a smaller size. His hand drawn letters eventually came down to 16pt size on 18pt leading.</p>

<h4><a href="http://linotypefilm.com/">Linotype: The Film</a></h4>

<p>Next we saw a <a href="http://linotypefilm.com">film about the Linotype machine</a>, in which some of the very few people who know how to operate <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linotype_machine">a Linotype machine</a> were interviewed. The Linotype revolutionized the printing industry, and was used from the 1890s through the 1960s.</p>

<h4><a href="http://urbanizedfilm.com/">Urbanized</a></h4>

<p><a href="http://urbanizedfilm.com/">Urbanized</a>, the third in Gary Hustwit&rsquo;s trilogy on design (after <a href="http://www.helveticafilm.com/">Helvetica</a> and <a href="http://www.objectifiedfilm.com/">Objectified</a>) drew attention to urban design. It featured cities in USA, Brazil, Germany, Columbia, South Africa, India, and China. Cities weren&rsquo;t something I thought of as being &#8220;designed&#8221;, but this movie changed the way I look at the world. Traffic patterns, bicycle lanes, highways, residential areas, sprawl: everything about a city is designed.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.iwatchstuff.com/2011/09/20/urbanized-trailer.jpg" alt="Urbanized" />
<em>From Urbanized</em></p>

<h3>Workshop Day</h3>

<p>I attended <a href="http://adactio.com">Jeremy Keith</a>&rsquo;s workshop on <a href="http://2011.buildconf.com/workshops">Responsive Enhancement</a>. Jeremy is a brilliant and original thinker. The workshop was so good, it will get its own blog post.</p>

<p><img src="http://distilleryimage11.s3.amazonaws.com/98c5e5540a2511e1abb01231381b65e3_7.jpg" alt="Workshop Day" />
<em>Workshop participants doing fancy workshop things</em></p>

<h3>An Evening with Erik Spiekermann</h3>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/#!/espiekermann">Erik Spikermann</a> is a world renowned typographer and designer. I saw him speak once before at <a href="http://www.underconsideration.com/brandnewconference/">Brand New Conference 2010</a> and he was every bit as entertaining and edgy then as at Build. He designed <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FF_Meta">Meta</a> and a handful of corporate typefaces. He is German and hilarious. One thing that really stuck out was hearing him talk about always using the best tools for the job, and then showing the <a href="http://edenspiekermann.com/">edenspiekermann</a> site technology stack, which included Ruby, Rails, and Padrino.  Though edenspiekermann is known for their design and branding, it is nice to see that they place importance on engineering. Oh, and he gave us this gem:</p>

<blockquote><p>We need topics and we need deadlines, otherwise we&rsquo;d be artists, and then we&rsquo;d sleep late and grow beards. And there&rsquo;s a difference between growing a beard and having a beard!</p></blockquote>

<h3>Practical Day</h3>

<p>Practical day served as an opportunity to collaborate with attendees, though I spent it as an opportunity to relax. Being an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/INFP">INFP</a>, nonstop socializing can become pretty tiresome. Putting a rest/leisure day in the middle of a conference is nothing short of brilliant.</p>

<h3>Conference Day</h3>

<p><img src="http://distilleryimage2.s3.amazonaws.com/02901e8c0c0b11e1a87612313804ec91_7.jpg" alt="The walk to conference day at Build Conf 2011" />
<em>Walking to the conference day at Build Conf</em></p>

<p>Build Conf offers a much more intimate atmosphere than most other conferences I attend. At other conferences, people are split between conference tracks, and there are too many attendees to count. At build, all attendees fit into the same room, and <a href="http://2011.buildconf.com/conference">the speakers</a> present one at a time. Here are notes on my three favorites:</p>

<p><strong><a href="http://52weeksofux.com/">Josh Brewer</a></strong>, design lead at Twitter, spoke about people, content, and devices, and the changing face of web design. He drove home the point that <em>We&rsquo;re not in Kansas anymore</em>, and we must embrace responsive design and the shift from desktop to mobile. Josh also talked about designer as avant-gardist, and shared this <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dieter_Rams">Dieter Rams</a> quote:</p>

<blockquote><p>I think that good designers must always be avant-gardists, always one step ahead of the times. They should &mdash; and must &mdash; question everything generally thought to be obvious. They must have an intuition for people&rsquo;s changing attitudes. For the reality in which they live, for their dreams, their desires, their worries, their needs, their living habits. They must also be able to assess realistically the opportunities and bounds of technology.</p></blockquote>

<p>Josh left us with a bit of practical advice, which I think more people need to hear:</p>

<blockquote><p>Start designing from your content. <br>
Stop designing from some imaginary page.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong><a href="http://craigmod.com/">Craig Mod</a></strong> spoke about the future of the book. He published a blog post, <em><a href="http://craigmod.com/journal/post_artifact/">Post-Artifact Books and Publishing</a></em>, and then released the same blog post as <a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B005568MZE/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;tag=cramod-20&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;camp=217153&amp;creative=399701&amp;creativeASIN=B005568MZE">a single </a> on the Amazon Kindle book store. He was amazed to find that people bought the single, even though it was available free of charge on his blog, and they could easily Instapaper it. <em>Why?</em> Craig believed that buying through a store offered a sense of curation, of boundaries and edges, though he saw it as a place to sell HTML. There is a revolution in the publishing industry right now, one that will be interesting to watch.</p>

<p><img id='wilson-miner' src='http://farm7.staticflickr.com/6222/6345941931_0f48955778_z.jpg' />
<em>Wilson Miner presenting at Build 2011. Photo credit to <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/fillyc/6345941931/sizes/z/in/set-72157628128834192/">fillyc</a>.</em></p>

<p><strong><a href="http://www.wilsonminer.com/">Wilson Miner</a></strong> gave one hell of a presentation. His presentation made the whole trip worthwhile. It had a different feel than the others; it was full of beautiful imagery and video, and music played in the background to support his most moving words. He started by speaking about the recent passing of his father, which hit <a href="http://www2.tntech.edu/its/FrankBush/default.asp">close to home</a>. He spoke of the things left behind by his father, and how he now had to deal with them. He then went on to talk about Marshall McLuhan and media over the past century, the key point being:</p>

<blockquote><p>We shape our tools. <br>
Our tools shape us.</p></blockquote>

<p>Man shaped the car, the car shaped man. Man shaped the television, the television shaped man. All of this leading up to the screen, the mobile device. Man shaped the screen, now the screen is shaping us.</p>

<blockquote><p>All the gaps in our lives are filling with screens.</p></blockquote>

<p>How much time passes between you waking up and viewing a screen? For me, it&#8217;s often less than a minute. The screen will reshape the human environment to as great a magnitude as did the car.</p>

<p>Wilson called to us to shape the future:</p>

<blockquote><p>We are the designers. We are the creators and builders. What do we want that future environment to feel like?</p></blockquote>

<p>He encouraged us to continue to learn and grow with this quote from Alistair Smith:</p>

<blockquote><p>At times of change, the learners are the ones who will inherit the world, while the knowers will be beautifully prepared for a world which no longer exists.</p></blockquote>

<p>And he closed with a powerful line that drew the whole presentation together, and summarized what Build meant to me:</p>

<blockquote><p>When we&#8217;re gone, the only thing that&#8217;s left of us is what we&#8217;ve made. So go out and build.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Organizing Page Specific JavaScript]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/08/22/organizing-page-specific-javascript/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/08/22/organizing-page-specific-javascript</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I often find myself repeating a JavaScript pattern, where I check for a DOM node&rsquo;s existence and fire a function if it&rsquo;s found. This weekend I put together a tiny jQuery plugin to abstract this pattern away into a more concise, readable format.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Big Poppa</h3>

<p>Big Poppa (<a href="https://github.com/wyattdanger/Big-Poppa">Github</a>) aims to simplify this pattern and make page specific JavaScript management a bit easier.</p>

<p><noscript><a href="https://gist.github.com/1163371">Example</a></noscript></p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/1163371.js"> </script>


<p>In each example, Poppa checks for the DOM nodes specified in the key, and passes the matching nodes into the callback function, only if the key was found in the DOM.</p>

<p>Poppa also looks pretty clean in <a href="http://jashkenas.github.com/coffee-script/">CoffeeScript</a>.
<noscript><a href="https://gist.github.com/1163444.js">Example</a></noscript></p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/1163444.js"> </script>


<p>Big Poppa is tiny (&lt; 0.2K minified) and available on <a href="https://github.com/wyattdanger/Big-Poppa">Github</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geocoding With Node.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/07/16/geocoding-with-nodejs/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/07/16/geocoding-with-nodejs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Need to make an asynchronous call to Google&#8217;s geocoding or reverse geocoding service in a Node.js application?  The <a href="https://github.com/wyattdanger/geocoder">Geocoder module</a> makes it simple to fetch geocoordinates based on street addresses, or to fetch localities based on LatLng pairs.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Adding the module to your project is easy, it is available as a <a href="http://search.npmjs.org/#/geocoder">npm package</a>. Just <code>npm install geocoder</code>. After requiring the module, it exposes two methods: <code>geocode</code> and <code>reverseGeocode</code>.</p>

<p><code>geocode</code> requires two arguments: a location in the form of a String, and a callback function which will accept the geodata returned from Google. The geodata will look like <a href="http://code.google.com/apis/maps/documentation/geocoding/#JSON">this</a>.</p>

<p><code>reverseGeocode</code> requires three arguments: a latitude, longitude, and callback function.</p>

<p>Both methods accept an optional last argument, an options Object which can pass along other Google API parameters, such as <code>sensor</code>, which defaults to false.</p>

<script src="https://gist.github.com/1086532.js" > </script>


<p>Of course, feel free to <a href="https://github.com/wyattdanger/geocoder">fork it on Github</a>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scraping Open Graph Metadata With Node]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/06/27/scraping-open-graph-metadata-with-node/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/06/27/scraping-open-graph-metadata-with-node</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>At <a href="http://convergese.com/">Converge SE</a> this weekend, I had the opportunity to attend a workshop on programming social web applications taught by Principal Software Enginner at Yahoo, <a href="http://www.jcleblanc.com/">Jonathan LeBlanc</a>.</p>

<p>One thing Jonathan covered was the <a href="http://ogp.me/">Open Graph Protocol</a>. Open Graph makes it easy for any developer to add metadata to their website pages. The data is primarily used control the title, description, image source, and URL to be displayed when their pages are shared on Facebook, but can be used by anybody.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Jonathan gave us a couple homework assignments during the presentation, one of which was to build an Open Graph metadata parser. Granted, Facebook already provides <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/tools/lint/">one of these</a>, but it proved to be a fun exercise in <a href="http://nodejs.org/">Node.js</a>. Using <a href="http://expressjs.com/">Express</a> I was able to build the parser in half an hour and then deploy to Heroku&#8217;s new <a href="http://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/cedar">Cedar stack</a> in a few minutes.</p>

<p>The app grabs the URL passed to it, renders the DOM on the server, and extracts the needed meta tags.</p>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/wyattdanger/og-lookup/">source</a> is available on Github and a <a href="http://og-quickcheck.herokuapp.com/">demo</a> is live on Heroku. Go ahead, give it a shot! I recommend looking up <a href="http://og-quickcheck.herokuapp.com/?url=http%3A%2F%2Fmailchimp.com">MailChimp</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Experience at Dev[Chatt]]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/06/07/my-experience-at-devchatt/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/06/07/my-experience-at-devchatt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had the opportunity to present on front-end Web performance optimization at <a href="http://devchatt.org/">DevChatt</a> this past weekend. It was a great small conference, with most panels covering topics related to front-end engineering or infrastructure.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Picking a topic was hard. This was my first conference speaking opportunity. After considering the work I&#8217;ve focused on in the past year, I decided that performance is something I&#8217;ve learned much about.</p>

<p>My slides are available <a href="http://wyattdanger.com/presentation.html">here</a> in HTML. To build the presentation I used <a href="https://github.com/n1k0/landslide">Landslide</a>, open-source software which parses a Markdown file and turns it into a full-featured HTML5 slideshow.</p>

<h4>Presentation I saw</h4>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://twitter.com/#!/crimondi">Chris Rimondi</a> on IPV6</li>
<li><a href="http://www.timmywillison.com/">Timmy Willison</a> of jQuery core on attr/prop in JQuery 1.6</li>
<li><a href="http://dryan.com">Daniel Ryan</a> on CSS3 <a href="http://dryan.com/css3">(slides)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://donaldsayers.com/">Donald Sayers</a> on <a href="http://paywallme.heroku.com/">Paywall.me</a></li>
<li><a href="http://dirolf.com/">Mike Dirolf</a> on <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/">MongoDB</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post on MailChimp Redesign]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/02/22/post-on-mailchimp-redesign/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2011/02/22/post-on-mailchimp-redesign</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have a post over on <a href="http://blog.mailchimp.com/building-the-new-mailchimp/">the MailChimp blog</a> about the process of designing and building the new site.</p>

<p>It is published with a <a href="http://blog.mailchimp.com/redesigning-mailchimp/">companion piece</a> from talented designer and coworker <a href="http://aaronrobbs.com">Aaron Robbs</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[DesignLab Blog On Unmatched Style]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2010/11/30/designlab-blog-on-unmatched-style/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2010/11/30/designlab-blog-on-unmatched-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Unmatched Style highlights the <a href="http://designlab.mailchimp.com/">DesignLab blog</a>’s SpaceInvaders design, and finds ASCII art in the source. They did not find the 404, though :)</p>

<p><img src="http://www.unmatchedstyle.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/10/designlabmailchimpcom.jpg" alt="DesignLab Blog Screenshot" /></p>

<p><a href="http://designlab.mailchimp.com/">Visit the DesignLab Blog</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2010 In Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2010/01/01/2010-in-review/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.stephenwyattbush.com/2010/01/01/2010-in-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Inspired by Seth Godin&rsquo;s <a href="1">What Did You Ship in 2010</a> post, I&rsquo;ve reflected on 2010 and listed things I&rsquo;ve shipped or accomplished this year.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ol>
<li><p>I started my first full-time job at <a href="http://thisismedium.com/">Medium</a>, and worked with the fine folks there to put the following sites into the world:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://riverstreetarchitecture.com/">River Street Architecture</a></li>
<li><a href="http://fsgbank.com/">FSGBank</a></li>
<li><a href="http://chattanoogafc.com/">Chattanooga FC</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.vo5haircare.com/home/">VO5 Haircare</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>2010 also had some pro-bono projects for friends and local Chattanooga folks:</p>

<ul>
<li>Designed and launched the <a href="http://utcart.com/">UTC Art</a> Department website</li>
<li>Built <a href="http://tyrickchristian.com/">Portfolio App</a> for Tyrick Christian</li>
<li>Built <a href="http://ncturner.com/">Portfolio App</a> for Nicholas Turner</li>
<li>Worked with some fun people to launch <a href="http://mainstreetbike.us/">Main Street Bike Co-op</a> site</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>In August I moved to Atlanta and started at <a href="http://www.mailchimp.com">MailChimp</a>, the best darn e-mail marketing company in the world. Some things done there so far include:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://designlab.mailchimp.com/">DesignLab Blog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://designlab.mailchimp.com/2010/designing-a-kickass-shirt-giveaway-experience/">Shirt App</a></li>
<li><a href="http://designlab.mailchimp.com/2010/2010-pizza-chart/">Pizza Chart</a></li>
<li>And more exciting projects are to come.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<p>Also some other things I&rsquo;m proud of, unrelated to work:</p>

<ul>
<li>Moved to Atlanta</li>
<li>Adopted a new cat, Max</li>
<li>Celebrated two years with Laura</li>
<li>Ran my first half marathon</li>
<li>Bought my first car</li>
<li>Quit smoking (10 months in after 5 years)</li>
</ul>


<p>And what would this be without a few resolutions?</p>

<ul>
<li>Run a half marathon in February</li>
<li>Run a full marathon in April</li>
<li>Contribute more in open source</li>
<li>Broaden my knowledge of languages and programming</li>
<li>Produce solid work in my new job at MailChimp</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
